JASON WANG

Senior Software Engineer

Panorama City, CA 91402 • (623) 223-7431

jason.wang.biz@outlook.com • www.linkedin.com/in/jason-wang-engineer

OBJECTIVES

Team-oriented and well-rounded software engineer with over 10 years of professional experience. Involved in building and maintaining software products across various industries and domains, including healthcare, real estate, e-commerce, fin-tech and construction. Committed to delivering excellence and collaborating with team members to consistently achieve project goals.

SKILLS

JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML, CSS, React.js, Next.js, Node.js, Express.js, Vue.js, Angular, RESTful API/GraphQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Ruby on Rails, Python/Django, AWS, Firebase, Jest/Enzyme, Cypress, Storybook

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Dodge Data & Analytics

Senior Software Engineer, 01/2020 – Present

- Built a cloud-based construction bid management application and successfully shipped to production with 100+ agencies and enterprises using the product.
- Implemented performant and user-friendly customer portal and admin dashboards with React.js.
- Devised and deployed Node.js / Python micro-services and serverless endpoints.
- Migrated 10+ front-end pages from React to Next.js, adopting various rendering strategies, enabling automatic code splitting, and improving developer experience.
- Followed pyramid testing approach, resulting in test coverage of over 80% across the entire stack.
- Collaborated closely with cross-functional teams while on-call to resolve production issues, resulting in around 50% reduction in churning ratio.

FACTS Computer Software House L.L.C.

Senior Software Engineer, 07/2016 – 11/2019

- Took ownership of a significant portion of the codebase, leading to substantial improvements in the stability, performance, and scalability of 4+ production apps.
- Migrated a legacy tele-dentistry healthcare platform from Angular.js to React using micro-frontend architecture, despite limited resources.
- Built a real estate geospatial data visualization and analysis platform using React and Node/Express.
- Built a people appreciation and celebration platform using Vue.js.
- Set up and follow best coding practices and standards to ensure high code quality with at least 75% of code coverage and less than 1% of duplicated code through SonarCloud.
- Provide mentorship with junior developers in the team.

Azinova Technologies

Web Developer, 05/2011 - 06/2016

- Collaborated with a full-stack team to modernize and enhance the innovative e-commerce platform.
- Committed to web development through successful completion of e-learning platform development and maintenance project.
- Achieved engineering maturity through rigorous training and practical exercises.

EDUCATION

University of DubaiBachelor's Degree in Computer Science, 2011